

□ (+86) 186-0068-0592 | **y**tjia.zju@gmail.com | **n**ytjia

## Summary.

Current Senior Algorithm Engineer in Didi Chuxing. 3+ years experience specializing in Machine Learning applications and Large-scale Data processing. Interested in designing and building Machine Learning applications to solve real-world problems, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises.

# **Work Experience**

Didi Chuxing Beijina, China

SENIOR ALGORITHM ENGINEER

Feb. 2016 - PRESENT

- Worked on SDP(Supply-Demand Prediction) project. Designed and built demand regression and supply-demand gap classification predictive model. Mined business features and implemented different state-of-art models to optimize model performance. Built and maintained SDP service used for Dispatching and Intelligent Marketing.
- Worked on Intelligent Marketing project. Designed and built user-activation, user-loss and bubble-order(like CTR) predictive model used for user targeting in Intelligent Marketing.

**Meituan**Beijing, China

DATA MINING ENGINEER

Jul. 2014 - Feb. 2016

- Worked on hotel ranking system. Implemented and maintained microservice of ranking system used for large-scale, real-time, personalized hotel searching. Designed and built machine learning pipeline for CTR and CVR model. Mined business features and implemented different state-of-art models to optimize CTR prediction. Resulted in paying rate increasing from 6% to 14%.
- Worked on channel traffic monitoring system. Built ETL pipeline to collect critical user actions like impression, click, order and refund and calculate according conversion rates at different stages. Presented important statistic results with dashboards and automated reports.
- Gain S score(<3%) twice in performance evaluations.

Meituan Beijing, China

Data Mining Engineer Intern Nov. 2013 - Apr. 2014

- · Worked on hotel customer profile mining. Used stats and machine-learning to find user order patterns in data.
- Worked on cheating device detection.

**Microsoft**Beijing, China

SOFTWARE DEVELOPENT ENGINEER INTERN

May. 2013 - Nov. 2013

- Participated in developing Bugsearcher(an internal tool) and it's monitoring service.
- Transplanted Ford's open source product AppLink from POSIX to Windows.

### **Education**

#### **ZJU (Zhejiang University)**

Hangzhou, China

M.S. IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

Sep. 2012 - Jun. 2014

# ZJU (Zhejiang University)

Hangzhou, China

B.S. IN ELECTRONIC AND INFORMATION ENGINEERING

Aug. 2008 - Jul. 2012

- Excellent Social Work Scholarship
- · Outstanding Student Leader Award

### **Skills**

**Programming** Python, Java, Scala, C, Bash

**Distributed Computing** Spark, Hive, Hadoop

**Machine Learning** scikit-learn, TensorFlow; LR, GBDT, LSTM and so on.

**Dev Tool** MacOS/Linux + IDEA/Vim + Git

**Product** Time Series Prediction, Intelligent Marketing, Learning to rank

September 18, 2017 Yitian Jia · Résumé 1